You can’t cross the same river twice, the popular saying goes.
有句俗语说，人不能两次踏入同一条河流。
This wisdom reminds us that everything changes - expecting to relive your bygone days of success in the same way is unrealistic.
这句至理名言提醒我们，万事万物都在变化——想要以同样的方式重温往日的成功岁月是不切实际的。
But, apparently, this doesn’t apply to music.
但显然，这个道理并不适用于音乐领域。
Over the last decade or so, for one reason or another, a number of high-profile bands have decided to stop resting on their laurels and have reunited.
在过去十年左右的时间里，不知出于何种原因，许多知名乐队决定不再满足于过去的成就，纷纷选择重组。
But why?
那么，他们重组的原因究竟是什么呢？
Earlier this year, rock band Genesis confirmed that they would be embarking on one more tour.
今年年初，摇滚乐队创世纪确认他们将再度开启巡演。
In November 2019, the Pussycat Dolls announced a slew of tour dates for April 2020.
2019年11月，小野猫组合宣布了2020年4月的一系列巡演日程。
In 2018, it was the Spice Girls’ comeback.
2018年，则是辣妹组合的回归之旅。
The list goes on.
类似的例子不胜枚举。
Many bands have found new success in their resurrected form.
许多乐队重组后再创辉煌。
American alternative rock band The Pixies originally broke up in 1993 after playing for seven years. After an eleven-year hiatus, the band reunited in 2004 and have not stopped.
美国另类摇滚乐队小妖精在成立七年后于1993年解散，经过十一年的沉寂，乐队于2004年重组，此后便一直活跃在乐坛。
In some cases, it’s financial reasons that made them go back on the road.
在某些情况下，经济因素是促使他们重返舞台的原因。
“Touring these days is far more lucrative than it used to be,” according to Kara Weisenstein of online publisher Mic.
在线媒体Mic的卡拉·韦森斯坦表示：“如今的巡演比以往利润丰厚得多。”
This is because ticket prices have risen to compensate for the piracy that weakened music sales in the 90s, according to online publisher Bloomberg.
据在线媒体彭博社报道，这是因为唱片盗版现象曾在20世纪90年代重创音乐销量，而如今演唱会票价的上涨正是对这一损失的弥补。
‘People are really into nostalgia right now,’ Lance Bass, member of former band NSYNC told Variety magazine.
前超级男孩组合成员兰斯·巴斯在接受《综艺》杂志采访时表示：“现在的人们特别热衷于怀旧。”
When The Pixies reformed, their 2004 comeback tour sold out within minutes.
小妖精乐队重组后，2004年的回归巡演门票几分钟内便销售一空。
Is it possible that those teenage fans of yore have grown into nostalgic adults wistful for their youth?
难道当年那些十几岁的年轻粉丝，如今都已长成怀念青春、渴望重温旧梦的成年人了吗？
Bass thinks so. ‘I think fans just want to feel that innocence and excitement again,’ he says.
巴斯对此深信不疑，他说：“我觉得粉丝们只是想再次体验那种纯真和激动的感觉。”
But not everybody thinks that these reunions are a good thing.
但并非所有人都认为乐队重组是件好事。
“There’s something noble in not trying to go after past glories,” says NME writer Leonie Cooper.
英国音乐杂志《新音乐快递》的撰稿人莱奥妮·库珀表示：“不追逐昔日辉煌，本身就是一种高尚的做法。”
‘As much as I love ABBA… the fact they refused to risk putting on a show that might not match the excellence of their heyday is pretty impressive.’
“我虽然非常喜欢阿巴合唱团……但他们拒绝冒险举办可能无法重现全盛时期水准的演出，这一点着实令人敬佩。”
Should bands reunite?
乐队到底该不该重组？
Opinion is divided.
人们对此意见不一。
If things don’t go well, they run the risk of being labelled has-beens and tarnishing their reputation.
如果重组后的表现不尽如人意，乐队就有可能被贴上“过气明星”的标签，声誉也会受损。
But if their sound is as good as it ever was and the fans are happy, then who’s going to complain?
但如果他们的音乐水准依然在线，粉丝们也为之欢欣雀跃，那么又有谁会抱怨呢？
After all, you can never have too much of a good thing.
毕竟，好东西永远不嫌多。